When you're running a press, the defense is running a press, one thing that you want to learn how to do, is break that press.
Hi, I'm Travis and I'm about to teach you exactly how you can do that, when you're on the basketball court.
Number one, when there is a press, a defensive press, what you want to make sure you do is, when you have the guy in, the person inbound the ball, you want to make sure that they have options.
Somewhere back here so that when they get in trouble, cause you don't want them out of bounds for five seconds, when they get in trouble, they can find someone to pass it to.
Usually, it'll be, you'll have two guards, you'll have your point guard, and your shooting guard back here.
And, what they'll do for each other, is they'll set screens, and when he or she smacks the ball, you'll have them split, to try to get open, once the ball is inbound and they get the ball, then that point guard or that shooting guard will take control of the game, and look for their options.
Now, the two guards are back here, you'll have, you may have the center all the way back or you may have the center somewhere closer to the top of the key, on the opposite top of the key.
But, you also want to have your forwards around half court, so that they have, so that your guards have options, if they get in trouble.
Now, you want to make sure that you pass the half court line within, within the time frame, the ten second time frame, but you want to also make sure that everybody is constantly moving cause you're breaking that press, there's pressure, there's going to be pressure that gets you, that's what the press is.
So, you want to have your offensive players down the court constantly moving, and constantly setting screens for each other, so they can get open.
Once, that is the key to breaking the press.
The press, once a guard has the ball, in the middle of the court, the press is pretty much broken, then the, then the thing is finding someone to pass it to, and getting it down court.
So, try your best to get that person, whoever is going to have the ball, after it's inbound to get into the middle of the court, so that they have options on the right, and on their left.
Once that happens, there you have it, breaking the press.